A Guide to the Papers of Clifton Waller Barrett, 1938-1983
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Clifton Waller Barrett, 1938-1983
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6526-o
This collection consists of ca. 400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of Mary Gilliam on 15 May 1995.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist chiefly of financial documents regarding banking accounts, securities and stock holdings of Barrett, his wife, and sons. Most are personal although a few involve Barrett's steamship lines. The collection also contains family photographs including one of Barrett at an English Speaking Union luncheon, an address book, and a movie of the dedication of the Barrett Room in Alderman Library.
Contents List
- Financial Papers
  - City Bank Farmers Trust Company 1951-1953
  - City Bank Farmers Trust Company: Cornelia H. Barrett 1946-1954
  - City Bank Farmers Trust Company: Barrett Children [John Sherwood Barrett; Richard Tupper Barrett; Robert Paul Barrett; William Hughes Barrett]
  - City Bank Farmers Tust Company: Purchase of Securities 1949-1954
  - City Bank Farmers Trust Company: Sale of Securities 1949-1954
  - City Bank Farmers Trust Company: Security Companies A.M. Kidder & Company; Bache & Company; H.C. Wainwright & Company; Kidder, Peabody, & Company; Spencer Trask & Company. 1949-1954
  - City Bank Farmers Trust Company: Special Account 1945-1955
  - Credit Advices 1938-1954
  - Cuban Dividends 1948-1953
  - Debit Advices 1946-1954
  - Havana Accounts 1951-1952
  - Havana Acounts: National Bank of New York 1951-1954
- Topical Materials
  - Address Book belonging to the Barretts n.d.
  - Photographs of Cornelia H. and Clifton Waller Barrett 1972, ca. 1983
- Movie film of the Dedication of the Barrett Room in Alderman Library at the University of Virginia. 1960